Victor Alagwu

Software Engineer Lagos, Nigeria +2348170449567

victoralagwu@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/victoralagwu | https://github.com/VictorAlagwu | https://stackoverflow.com/users/4182278/victor-alagwu | https://victoralagwu.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer, who tries to emphasize on good design and code quality, my speciality is in backend development, though sometimes I work on the frontend aspect of software development, My technical expertise spans through years of experience with solving problems using PHP and Javascript in different industries e.g Fintech, Health, Value-Added Services, Digital Agency etc.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: PHP, Javascript, Golang, HTML5, CSS **Frameworks/Libraries/CMS:** Laravel, React, WordPress,NodeJS

Database: MySQL, Postgres, Redis

Tools: Linux, AWS (S3 and SES), CentOS, Git, Graylog, RabbitMQ, Ubuntu, Apache, Nginx **DevOps Practise and Processes:** Docker, Kubernetes (Rancher), CircleCI, Travis CI, Continuous

Integration and Continous Delivery, Test Driven Development (PHPUnit)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sellsio CRM - Bath, United Kingdom Software Engineer, Full-Time (Remote)

November 2020 - Present

- Added a new integration to capture the users' schedule appointments and events
- Optimise the frontend and backend code to ensure faster response time

TM30 Global Limited, - Lagos, Nigeria Software Engineer, Full-Time

AUGUST 2018 - OCTOBER 2020

- Built backend systems for SFSCredit loan application, that allows employees of different onboarded companies to request soft loans.
- Collaborated with a team of engineers to scale most of the company's projects from vertical to horizontal scaling using Kubernetes.
- Involved in the development of a utility payment service, that enables users to pay their utility bills using WhatsApp bot
- Managed the deployment and containerization of some of the company's products
- Worked on the integration of third-party APIs and payment processors in projects.
- Developed the backend for a savings application (AdashiEsusuAkawo.com), that revolutionizes traditional Nigeria esusu saving activity
- Collaborated with a team of three backend developers, to create micro-services e.g

- User Service, Notification Service etc, that helped reduce projects development time, and speed up deployment time for in-house projects
- Restructured and refactor the backend system for MyEduSponsor, a computer-based test system that awards sponsorships and gifts to eligible participants
- Developed documentation for endpoints; helps increases the productivity of the frontend developer

PJ Engineering and Business Solutions Pty. Ltd, (RocketLaunchr.cloud) - Melbourne, Australia

Software Developer, Part-Time (Remote)

JANUARY 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

- Revamped documentation templates for some of the company open source projects e.g Electron.guide,
- Improved the dashboard for the Cucumber.app, a desktop app that helps reduce eye strain by restricting a user's access to his laptop for some minutes.
- Managed and ensured the smooth on-boarding of new team additions

Inclusive Design Research Centre (Google Summer of Code'18) - Toronto, Canada Software Developer (Remote)

MAY 2018 - AUGUST 2018

- Overhauled the obsolete legacy source code of AChecker, resulting in increased usability and reduced load time by 50%
- Implemented plates templating engine as a replacement to savant2 templating engine being used in AChecker
- Awarded a Google Summer of Code certificate for completing most of my tasks during the program period
- Project Details:

https://gist.github.com/VictorAlagwu/ded80c52cc8c927f7f857bd26cb05f5c

Heimdall Technologies - Abuja, Nigeria Software Developer (Contract)

March 2018 - April 2018

• Developed an education portal using WordPress

TM30 Global Limited - Lagos, Nigeria Software Developer (Internship)

AUGUST 2017 - DECEMBER 2017

• Designed and configured web portals for value-added services

EDUCATION

University of Nigeria, Nsukka, Enugu State, Nigeria

SEPTEMBER 2014 - AUGUST 2018

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science